DAVID SHERIDAN

PROFILE



21 Archers Wood Green,
Archers Wood,
Delgany,
Co. Wicklow

davidsheridandsgn@gmail.com D.O.B. 05/09/1991 0851337449 I'm a freelance digital product designer & user researcher who aims to create engaging solutions to complex design challenges.

Experienced in designing & developing user–centred applications across web & mobile, in both in–house & agency environments alongside teams of designers, developers & product managers.

Education

2017-2019

MSc in User Experience Design from IADT.

2011-2015

 B.A. Honours degree in Visual Communications from IADT.

EXPERIENCE

David Sheridan Design

Freelance Digital Product Designer & User Researcher April 2024 – Present

I work with businesses to help them understand their clients through research & engage with them through design solutions that drive business value.

Services include:

- Competitor analysis.
- Qualitative user research
- Quantitative user research.
- Summary research report.
- Roadmap development with MVP recommendations.
- Low-fidelity interaction designs & prototyping.
- High-fidelity UI design & prototyping.
- Collaborating with developers to implement designs
- Implementing Mixpanel dashboards.

Nory Al

Senior Digital Product Designer July 2023 – April 2024

Responsible for leading the product & design direction of Nory's Inventory Management offering. This work is done in collaboration with the CEO, head of design, engineering team lead & a team of developers across both our desktop & mobile platforms.

Responsibilities include:

- Competitor analysis.
- Remote & in-person user research.
- Developing & maintaining team backlog.
- Planning team quarterly roadmap alongside CEO, Head of Design & engineering team lead.
- Designing user journeys & wireframes.
- Creating prototypes in Figma.
- UI design.
- Collaborating with developers to implement designs
- Implementing & monitoring Mixpanel dashboards
- Presenting new releases at weekly company call.
- Facilitating educational workshops for new hires.
- Sharing team lead responsibilities.

DAVID SHERIDAN

EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

Glofox

Senior Digital Product Designer November 2020 – July 2023

Responsible for leading the design direction of Glofox Services, used by clients to set up & sell services such as memberships to their customers. This work is done in collaboration with the head of design, multiple product managers, designers, engineering team leads & teams of developers across both our desktop & mobile platforms.

Responsibilities include:

- Mentoring designers in user research & communication skills.
- Standardising the company's research principles & practices alongside the head of design.
- Contributing design components & updates to the design system.

- Participating in the hiring process of potential candidates alongside the head of design.
- Helping to onboard new designers.
- Competitor analysis.
- Heuristic analysis.
- Remote & in-person user research.
- Working with product managers & engineering teams to plan out projects through user story mapping.
- Designing user journeys & wireframes.
- Information architecture design.
- Creating prototypes in Figma and Protopie.
- UI design.
- Collaborating with developers to implement designs.
- Regularly presenting work to the company at bi-weekly all hands.

Storyful

Digital Product Designer October 2017 – May 2019 Senior Digital Product Designer June 2019 – November 2020

Responsible for designing & improving the user experience of an internal web-based application used by teams of journalists & analysts to search & analyse social media data. This is done within a scrum team of developers & a product owner.

Other responsibilities include leading research initiatives & the design direction of the design system alongside a leadership panel containing the lead designer & lead developers.

Responsibilities include:

- Mentoring designers in user research & interaction design.
- Leading the user research guild & the company's customer research initiative.

- Leading the design direction & governance structure of the design system alongside the lead designer & lead developers.
- Competitor analysis.
- Remote & in-person user research.
- Working with the product owner to define the quarterly product roadmap.
- Designing user journeys & wireframes.
- Heuristic analysis.
- Creating prototypes in InVision.
- UI design.
- Collaborating with developers to implement designs.
- Information architecture design.
- Communicating design updates through presentations
 & the company blog.

DAVID SHERIDAN

EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

Isobar

User Experience Designer August 2016 – October 2017

Responsible for designing & improving the user experience of new & existing websites within a team of designers & developers.

PatientBuddy

Digital Product Designer July 2015 – July 2016

Responsible for designing web & mobile applications for medical conditions ranging from prostate cancer to kidney transplants, within an in-house team of designers & developers.

Maithú IT Solutions

Digital Product Designer July 2015 – July 2016

Responsible for designing improvements & implementing front end updates for the in–house medical app 'Medical E-Guides' within a team of designers & developers.

PUBLICATIONS

#AreYouFollowingMe?

An Analysis of UI Design & User Behaviour in Social Media

The Development of Trust & Cognitive Load in Human-Automation Interaction

Evaluating the Impact of Visualisation Techniques on Results of Automated Desktop Applications.

TALKS

Engineering Management Ireland

January 2020

Creating a Research Guild to Build Leadership Skills
Gave a talk that discussed my personal experiences of
developing leadership skills through creating a
research guild, with recommendations given.

UXDX Community Meetup

May 2020

Utilising Guilds to Develop a Culture of Research
Delivered a talk that discussed the development of
a research culture & practices within an Agile Scrum
environment through the development of a research guild.
Examples & successful milestones were discussed with
recommendations given.